<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Doodle Verse</string>

    <string name="color_palette">Color Palette</string>
    <string name="add_custom_color">Add custom color</string>
    <string name="move">Move</string>
    <string name="toggle_visibility">Toggle visibility</string>
    <string name="delete_layer">Delete layer</string>
    <string name="layer_preview">Layer preview</string>
    <string name="add_new_layer">Add new layer</string>
    <string name="opacity">Opacity</string>
    <string name="drag_handle">Drag handle</string>
    <string name="new_project">New project</string>
    <string name="edit_project">Edit project</string>
    <string name="project_name">Project Name</string>
    <string name="cancel">Cancel</string>
    <string name="save">Save</string>
    <string name="template">Template</string>
    <string name="create">Create</string>
    <string name="back">Back</string>

    <string name="about_app_title">About DoodleVerse</string>
    <string name="version_number">Version %1$s</string>
    <string name="features">Features</string>
    <string-array name="features_list">
        <item>Cross-platform drawing application</item>
        <item>Multiple brush types and tools</item>
        <item>Layer system for complex artworks</item>
        <item>Real-time preview of changes</item>
        <item>Project management system</item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="about_app_description">DoodleVerse is your creative companion for digital art. Whether you're a beginner or professional artist, DoodleVerse offers the tools you need to bring your imagination to life.</string>
    <string name="developed_by">Developed by</string>
    <string name="developer_name">TaalayDev</string>
    <string name="visit_website">Visit website</string>

    <string name="undo">Undo</string>
    <string name="redo">Redo</string>
    <string name="clear">Clear</string>
    <string name="save_image">Save Image</string>
    <string name="share_image">Share Image</string>
    <string name="import_image">Import Image</string>
    <string name="color">Color</string>
    <string name="brush">Brush</string>
    <string name="eraser">Eraser</string>
    <string name="fill">Fill</string>
    <string name="shapes">Shapes</string>
    <string name="line">Line</string>
    <string name="rectangle">Rectangle</string>
    <string name="circle">Circle</string>
    <string name="ellipse">Ellipse</string>
    <string name="polygon">Polygon</string>
    <string name="brush_settings">Brush Settings</string>
    <string name="layers">Layers</string>
    <string name="eyedropper">Eyedropper</string>
    <string name="zoom">Zoom</string>
    <string name="move_tool">Move Tool</string>
    <string name="selection_tool">Selection Tool</string>
    <string name="brush_size">Brush size</string>

    <string name="projects">Projects</string>
    <string name="create_new_project">Create New Project</string>
    <string name="lessons">Lessons</string>
    <string name="about">About</string>
    <string name="no_projects_found">No projects found</string>
    <string name="create_new">Create New</string>
    <string name="more_options">More options</string>
    <string name="delete">Delete</string>
    <string name="edit">Edit</string>
    <string name="just_now">Just now</string>
    <string name="minutes_ago">%1$dm ago</string>
    <string name="hours_ago">%1$dh ago</string>
    <string name="days_ago">%1$dd ago</string>

    <string name="pen">Pen</string>
    <string name="previous">Prev</string>
    <string name="next">Next</string>
    <string name="step">Step</string>
    <string name="step_count">Step %1$d</string>
    <string name="step_count_of">Step %1$d of %2$d</string>
    <string name="start_drawing">Start Drawing</string>
    <string name="completed">Completed</string>
    <string name="ready_to_draw">Ready to draw?</string>
    <string name="ready_to_draw_description">You've learned all the steps! Would you like to start drawing now?\nYou can always come back to review the lesson later.</string>
    <string name="not_yet">Not yet</string>

    <string name="all_categories">All Categories</string>
    <string name="category_animals">Animals</string>
    <string name="category_anime">Anime</string>

    <string name="difficulty">Difficulty</string>
    <string name="difficulty_easy">Easy</string>
    <string name="difficulty_medium">Medium</string>
    <string name="difficulty_hard">Hard</string>

    <string name="extract_colors">Extract Colors</string>

    <string name="copy_layer">Copy Layer</string>
    <string name="clear_layer">Clear Layer</string>
    <string name="merge_down">Merge Down</string>
    <string name="rename_layer">Rename Layer</string>
    <string name="edit_layer_name">Edit Layer Name</string>
    <string name="layer_name">Layer Name</string>

    <!-- Layer states -->
    <string name="empty_layer">Empty Layer</string>
    <string name="layer_opacity">Opacity: %d%%</string>

    <string name="chibi_dog_lesson_title">Dog</string>
    <string name="chibi_dog_lesson_description">Learn how to draw a dog</string>
    <string name="chibi_dog_lesson_1_description">Start by drawing a large circle to form the base shape of the chibi dog's head. This circle will serve as the foundation for the character's face.</string>
    <string name="chibi_dog_lesson_2_description">Add curved lines to outline the sides of the face, creating chubby cheeks and a slight point for the chin.</string>
    <string name="chibi_dog_lesson_3_description">Add two large triangular shapes on top of the head for the ears. Position them symmetrically and add smaller inner triangles to create the inner ear details.</string>
    <string name="chibi_dog_lesson_4_description">Draw two large oval shapes for the eyes, positioning them near the center of the head. Add small circles inside the eyes to represent the pupils.</string>
    <string name="chibi_dog_lesson_5_description">Add a small, curved line below the eyes to form the nose. Draw a small, curved line below the nose to create the mouth.</string>
    <string name="chibi_dog_lesson_6_description">Enhance the dog's expression by adding additional details to the face as in the guidelines.</string>
    <string name="chibi_dog_lesson_7_description">Erase the unnecessary guideline elements while retaining the essential parts like the curved outlines of the face and ears. This step refines the drawing and prepares it for further details.</string>
    <string name="chibi_dog_lesson_8_description">Sketch the chibi dog's body with rounded, soft edges. Add the front legs, keeping them symmetrical, and shape the paws with simple curves.</string>
    <string name="chibi_dog_lesson_9_description">Draw the chibi dog's tail with a curved, fluffy shape. Add a zigzag pattern along the edge to emphasize the fluffiness and make it look lively.</string>
    <string name="chibi_dog_lesson_10_description">To enhance the dog's appearance, add some fluffy fur details to its chest and legs. Draw curved, jagged lines to indicate soft fur.</string>
    <string name="chibi_dog_lesson_11_description">Review your drawing and make any necessary adjustments to refine the lines and details. Erase any remaining guidelines and ensure the drawing is clean and polished.</string>

    <string name="simple_cat_lesson_title">Cat</string>
    <string name="simple_cat_lesson_description">Learn how to draw a cat</string>
    <string name="simple_cat_lesson_1_description">Start by drawing a large circle to form the base shape of the cat's head. This circle will help define the overall size and placement of the head for your drawing.</string>
    <string name="simple_cat_lesson_2_description">Draw the outline of the cat's cheeks and jawline by creating two curved lines that extend outward from the bottom sides of the circle.</string>
    <string name="simple_cat_lesson_3_description">Connect the two cheeks by drawing a smooth curved line at the bottom to form the cat’s chin.</string>
    <string name="simple_cat_lesson_4_description">Erase the left and right parts of the initial circle, leaving only the cheeks and chin lines intact.</string>
    <string name="simple_cat_lesson_5_description">Add two large, triangular ears at the top of the head. Position them symmetrically on either side, slightly angled outward.</string>
    <string name="simple_cat_lesson_6_description">Inside the face, draw two large oval shapes for the eyes. Position them symmetrically near the middle of the head.</string>
    <string name="simple_cat_lesson_7_description">Draw a slightly larger oval around each of the existing eyes to create an outline.</string>
    <string name="simple_cat_lesson_8_description">Erase the overlapping or unused parts of the outer eye outlines to clean up the drawing. Keep only the parts that create a smooth, complete shape around each eye.</string>
    <string name="simple_cat_lesson_9_description">Add a small upside-down triangle in the center of the face to form the cat’s nose. Below the nose, draw two curved lines that extend downward and outward to create the mouth.</string>
    <string name="simple_cat_lesson_10_description">Draw small curved lines above each eye to create the eyebrows. These lines should be slightly arched to add expression to the cat’s face. Next, draw two small circles on either side of the mouth area to represent the cheeks.</string>
    <string name="simple_cat_lesson_11_description">Sketch two oval shapes at the bottom of the face for the front paws. Position them symmetrically on each side, curving slightly inward to give a natural sitting pose. Add two short, curved lines on each paw to indicate the toes.</string>
    <string name="simple_cat_lesson_12_description">Draw four small oval shapes at the bottom of each front paw to create the toes. Arrange them side by side, ensuring they are evenly spaced and proportionate to the paw.</string>
    <string name="simple_cat_lesson_13_description">Add two short, curved lines on each paw to indicate the toes.</string>
    <string name="simple_cat_lesson_14_description">Draw a small, pointed shape at the bottom center of the cat’s head, resembling a tuft of fur.</string>
    <string name="simple_cat_lesson_15_description">Sketch a long, curved tail on the side of the cat. Start from the bottom near the paws and curve it outward, giving it a slightly fluffy appearance by adding a small zigzag line near the tip.</string>
    <string name="simple_cat_lesson_16_description">Review your drawing and add any final details or adjustments to enhance the cat's appearance. Erase any remaining guidelines and refine the lines for a clean and polished look. </string>

    <string name="chibi_girl_lesson_title">Anime chibi girl</string>
    <string name="chibi_girl_lesson_description">Learn how to draw an anime chibi girl</string>
    <string name="chibi_girl_lesson_1_description">Begin by drawing a large circle to represent the base shape of the head. This circle will act as the foundation for the chibi character's face.</string>
    <string name="chibi_girl_lesson_2_description">Add two small, curved shapes on each side of the head to form the ears. Position them slightly below the top of the circle, ensuring they are symmetrical.</string>
    <string name="chibi_girl_lesson_3_description">Sketch two long, curved lines on each side of the head to create the outline of the hair. These lines should flow naturally from the top of the head down toward the cheeks, framing the face.</string>
    <string name="chibi_girl_lesson_4_description">Draw a few pointed, triangular shapes at the top of the head to represent individual hair strands. Let these shapes flow naturally downward toward the face, overlapping slightly.</string>
    <string name="chibi_girl_lesson_5_description">Draw the full outline of the hair, connecting the previously added strands with smooth, flowing lines.</string>
    <string name="chibi_girl_lesson_6_description">Erase the parts of the initial circle guideline that overlap with the hair and face. This step refines the drawing, leaving only the detailed hair and head outline.</string>
    <string name="chibi_girl_lesson_7_description">Inside the face, add two large oval shapes for the eyes. Position them symmetrically near the center of the head.</string>
    <string name="chibi_girl_lesson_8_description">Draw curved lines above each eye to create the eyelashes. Extend the lines slightly outward for a more expressive and charming look.</string>
    <string name="chibi_girl_lesson_9_description">Draw two small, curved lines above the eyes to form the eyebrows. Position them symmetrically and slightly above the eyelashes.</string>
    <string name="chibi_girl_lesson_10_description">Draw a tiny curved line in the center of the face for the nose. Below it, add a small, curved smile to form the mouth.</string>
    <string name="chibi_girl_lesson_11_description">Begin sketching the top of the dress by drawing a small, rounded neckline below the head.</string>
    <string name="chibi_girl_lesson_12_description">Extend the neckline downward to create the main body of the dress. Draw two slightly flared lines outward to form the dress's shape, giving it a flowing and relaxed appearance.</string>
    <string name="chibi_girl_lesson_13_description">Draw small, curved lines extending outward from the top of the dress to form the sleeves.</string>
    <string name="chibi_girl_lesson_14_description">Sketch two small, curved lines extending downward from the sleeves to form the arms. Position them symmetrically on each side, keeping the lines simple and slightly rounded to match the chibi style.</string>
    <string name="chibi_girl_lesson_15_description">Extend the bottom of the dress to form the skirt. Draw slightly flared, curved lines outward to give the skirt a flowing appearance.</string>
    <string name="chibi_girl_lesson_16_description">Extend two simple, slightly curved lines downward from the bottom of the skirt to form the legs.</string>
    <string name="chibi_girl_lesson_17_description">Add flowing lines extending downward from each side of the head to lengthen the hair.</string>
    <string name="chibi_girl_lesson_18_description">Take a moment to review your drawing and refine any lines that need adjustment. Erase any unnecessary guidelines and ensure all elements are smooth and polished.</string>

    <string name="simple_frog_lesson_title">How to Draw a Cute Frog</string>
    <string name="simple_frog_lesson_description">Learn how to draw a cute frog</string>
    <string name="simple_frog_lesson_1_description">Start with an oval, slightly stretched horizontally. This will be the base for your frog's head. Make sure the top part of the oval is smoothly rounded, while the bottom is slightly flatter. Leave space for the eyes, which will be added later.</string>
    <string name="simple_frog_lesson_2_description">Draw two large semicircles on the sides of the upper part of the head. These semicircles will serve as the base for the frog's eyes.</string>
    <string name="simple_frog_lesson_3_description">Inside each semicircle, draw small circles to represent pupils. Add tiny dots for highlights to make the eyes look more expressive.</string>
    <string name="simple_frog_lesson_4_description">Draw a small curved mouth in the center of the lower part of the head to give the frog a friendly expression. Add a small circle on each side of the mouth to represent cheeks.</string>
    <string name="simple_frog_lesson_5_description">At the bottom of the head, add two curved lines extending diagonally downward and inward. These will be the frog's arms. Ensure the lines are slightly bent to make them look natural.</string>
    <string name="simple_frog_lesson_6_description">Extend the lines representing the arms downward to create the body outline. Draw two curved lines on each side extending from the lower part of the body.</string>
    <string name="simple_frog_lesson_7_description">Add triangular shapes at the ends of the lines representing the back legs to create the feet.</string>
    <string name="simple_frog_lesson_8_description">Draw an oval underneath the frog, representing a mound or lily pad that the frog is sitting on.</string>
    <string name="simple_frog_lesson_9_description">Take a moment to review your drawing and make any necessary adjustments. Erase any unnecessary guidelines and ensure all lines are smooth and polished.</string>

    <string name="anime_eyes_lesson_title">Basic Anime Eye Drawing</string>
    <string name="anime_eyes_lesson_description">Learn how to draw basic anime eyes</string>
    <string name="anime_eyes_lesson_1_description">Draw a perfect circle as the foundation for your anime eye. This creates the basic outline and establishes the size and position on your character's face.</string>
    <string name="anime_eyes_lesson_2_description">Draw the upper and lower eyelid lines. Make the top line thicker and more curved, while the bottom line should be thinner and less curved, creating the almond eye shape.</string>
    <string name="anime_eyes_lesson_3_description">Erase the top part of your circle, keeping only the upper eyelid line. This creates the foundation for the classic anime eye shape with its distinctive curved upper lid.</string>
    <string name="anime_eyes_lesson_4_description">Add the iris and pupil by drawing a filled black circle within your eye outline. Include two highlights - a larger unfilled circle and a small white dot - to give the eye depth and a lifelike sparkle.</string>
    <string name="anime_eyes_lesson_5_description">Add eyelashes by drawing short diagonal lines extending from the upper eyelid. Make them thicker at the base and thinner at the tips for a natural look.</string>
    <string name="anime_eyes_lesson_6_description">Draw the eyebrow by creating a curved line above the eye. Make it slightly thicker than the top eyelid line and position it at a comfortable distance above the eye to create a natural expression.</string>
    <string name="anime_eyes_lesson_7_description">Take a moment to review your drawing and make any necessary adjustments. Erase any unnecessary guidelines and ensure all lines are smooth and polished.</string>

    <string name="cat_lesson_title">Cute Cat</string>
    <string name="cat_lesson_description">Learn how to draw a simple and cute cat.</string>
    <string name="cat_lesson_1_description">Start by drawing a circle for the head. On top of the circle, add two pointed, triangular shapes for the ears.</string>
    <string name="cat_lesson_2_description">Below the head, draw the body and front legs. Sketch two lines curving downwards and inwards, ending in two small paws.</string>
    <string name="cat_lesson_3_description">Add the back legs by drawing two curved lines on either side of the body. Complete each leg with a small, rounded paw at the bottom.</string>
    <string name="cat_lesson_4_description">Draw a long, looping tail starting from the side of the cat's body.</string>
    <string name="cat_lesson_5_description">Finally, add the facial features. Draw two oval eyes, a small nose, and a mouth. Don't forget to add whiskers and two small lines for eyebrows.</string>
    <string name="cat_lesson_6_description">Review your drawing and erase any unnecessary lines. Your cute cat is complete!</string>

    <string name="hair_lesson_title">How to Draw Anime Hair</string>
    <string name="hair_lesson_description">Learn the basic steps to draw a common anime hairstyle.</string>
    <string name="hair_lesson_1_description">First, lightly sketch a basic head shape. This will act as a guide to ensure the hair fits correctly.</string>
    <string name="hair_lesson_2_description">Next, define the hairline. Draw two curved lines that meet at a central point to create the part for the bangs.</string>
    <string name="hair_lesson_3_description">Draw the outer shape of the hair. Use large, curved lines that flow over the top of the head guideline to create volume.</string>
    <string name="hair_lesson_4_description">Add detail by drawing smaller sections. Sketch pointed shapes to form the bangs and add longer, flowing locks on the sides.</string>
    <string name="hair_lesson_5_description">Finally, erase the initial head guideline and refine your lines. You've successfully drawn a basic anime hairstyle!</string>

    <string name="anime_girl_face_lesson_title">How to Draw an Anime Girl Face</string>
    <string name="anime_girl_face_lesson_description">Follow these steps to draw a classic anime girl's face.</string>
    <string name="anime_girl_face_lesson_1_description">Start with a circle and add horizontal and vertical guidelines. This will help you place the facial features correctly.</string>
    <string name="anime_girl_face_lesson_2_description">Using the circle as a guide, draw the jawline, a pointed chin, and two curved lines for the neck.</string>
    <string name="anime_girl_face_lesson_3_description">Lightly sketch the placement guides for the facial features. Use the horizontal line to position the eyes, and add marks for the eyebrows, nose, and mouth.</string>
    <string name="anime_girl_face_lesson_4_description">Refine the eye shapes, adding pupils and highlights to make them expressive. Draw the final form of the nose.</string>
    <string name="anime_girl_face_lesson_5_description">Begin drawing the hair. Sketch the bangs framing the forehead and add the curved outline for the top of the hair to create volume.</string>
    <string name="anime_girl_face_lesson_6_description">Add long, flowing locks of hair on the sides of the face. Complete the expression by drawing the eyebrows above the eyes.</string>
    <string name="anime_girl_face_lesson_7_description">Erase all the initial guidelines. Refine your lines and add any final details to complete your drawing.</string>

    <string name="fox_lesson_title">Fox</string>
    <string name="fox_lesson_description">Learn how to draw a simple, elegant fox.</string>
    <string name="fox_lesson_1_description">Start by drawing the head in profile. Sketch a long, pointed snout, two triangular ears, and a small dot for the eye.</string>
    <string name="fox_lesson_2_description">Next, draw the body. Use a long, curved line for the back and add a few short, simple lines underneath to suggest the legs.</string>
    <string name="fox_lesson_3_description">Draw the large, bushy tail. Add a zigzag line near the end to show the iconic white tip of the fox's tail.</string>
    <string name="fox_lesson_4_description">Connect all the parts and review your drawing. Erase any stray marks to complete your simple fox.</string>

    <string name="penguin_lesson_title">Penguin</string>
    <string name="penguin_lesson_description">Learn how to draw a cute and simple penguin.</string>
    <string name="penguin_lesson_1_description">Start by drawing two overlapping circles, with the top circle slightly smaller than the bottom one.</string>
    <string name="penguin_lesson_2_description">Connect the circles with smooth, curved lines to create the basic body shape of the penguin.</string>
    <string name="penguin_lesson_3_description">Add a small triangular beak in the center of the top part of the body. Above the beak, draw two small dots for the eyes and simple curved lines for the wings extending from the sides.</string>
    <string name="penguin_lesson_4_description">Draw two small, webbed feet at the bottom of the penguin's body. You can add a few short, curved lines on the body to suggest feathers.</string>
    <string name="penguin_lesson_5_description">Review your drawing and erase any unnecessary lines. Your simple penguin is now complete!</string>

    <string name="rose_lesson_title">Rose</string>
    <string name="rose_lesson_description">Learn how to draw a simple rose starting with a heart shape.</string>
    <string name="rose_lesson_1_description">Begin by drawing a heart shape. Below it, draw a single curved line for the stem.</string>
    <string name="rose_lesson_2_description">Refine the heart into a rosebud shape by making the sides more elongated and adding a small curve at the top opening. Thicken the stem.</string>
    <string name="rose_lesson_3_description">Draw a small spiral in the upper center of the bud. This creates the look of coiled inner petals.</string>
    <string name="rose_lesson_4_description">Add details to the stem by drawing two pointed leaves. You can also add small sepals just below the flower.</string>
    <string name="rose_lesson_5_description">Review your drawing, erase any initial guidelines, and refine the lines to complete your beautiful rose.</string>

    <string name="turtle_lesson_title">Turtle</string>
    <string name="turtle_lesson_description">Learn to draw a cute turtle by combining simple shapes.</string>
    <string name="turtle_lesson_1_description">Start with the head. Draw a circle and add two dots for eyes and a simple curved line for a smile.</string>
    <string name="turtle_lesson_2_description">Next, draw a large semicircle or a dome shape for the turtle's shell.</string>
    <string name="turtle_lesson_3_description">Add a small, curved tail to one side of the shell.</string>
    <string name="turtle_lesson_4_description">Draw four small, rounded U-shapes for the feet, placing them along the bottom edge of the shell.</string>
    <string name="turtle_lesson_5_description">Give the shell some detail by drawing an interconnected pattern of lines on its surface.</string>
    <string name="turtle_lesson_6_description">Finally, connect the head to the shell and review your drawing. Erase any extra lines to complete your cute turtle!</string>

    <string name="nose_front_lesson_title">How to Draw a Nose</string>
    <string name="nose_front_lesson_description">Learn to draw a nose from a front-facing perspective.</string>
    <string name="nose_front_lesson_1_description">Begin by drawing a circle. This will serve as a guideline for the fleshy tip of the nose.</string>
    <string name="nose_front_lesson_2_description">Next, draw an inverted triangle over the circle. The extended top line will represent the brow line, and the sides will guide the placement of the nose's bridge.</string>
    <string name="nose_front_lesson_3_description">Inside the bottom of the triangle, sketch two small, dark, curved shapes to represent the nostrils.</string>
    <string name="nose_front_lesson_4_description">Add two simple curved lines, similar to parentheses, on either side of the nostrils to define the wings of the nose.</string>
    <string name="nose_front_lesson_5_description">Finally, erase the initial guidelines. Add shading around the wings and under the tip to give the nose dimension and form.</string>
    <string name="nose_front_lesson_6_description">Review your drawing, refine the lines, and add any final details to complete your nose drawing.</string>

    <string name="nose_lesson_title">How to Draw a Nose</string>
    <string name="nose_lesson_description">Learn a simple method for drawing a nose from a 3/4 view.</string>
    <string name="nose_lesson_1_description">Start by lightly sketching an oval. This will serve as the guideline for the ball at the tip of the nose.</string>
    <string name="nose_lesson_2_description">Add construction lines. Draw a curved line for the bridge of the nose and intersecting lines to map out the placement of the nostrils.</string>
    <string name="nose_lesson_3_description">Begin to define the final shape. Using your guidelines, draw the detailed curve of the nostril and the wing on one side.</string>
    <string name="nose_lesson_4_description">Complete the nose by drawing the other nostril and the simple curve that suggests the other side of the nose.</string>
    <string name="nose_lesson_5_description">Erase your initial guidelines. You can add shading and highlights to give the nose more dimension and a realistic look.</string>

    <string name="hand_lesson_title">How to Draw a Simple Hand</string>
    <string name="hand_lesson_description">Follow these easy steps to draw a basic hand.</string>
    <string name="hand_lesson_1_description">Begin by drawing a shape that is slightly wider at the top, like a rounded trapezoid. This will form the palm of the hand.</string>
    <string name="hand_lesson_2_description">Next, add a triangular shape to the side for the thumb. Sketch out the basic placement of the fingers by connecting them to the palm.</string>
    <string name="hand_lesson_3_description">Draw the four fingers extending from the top of the palm. Keep them as simple rectangular shapes and add small curved lines at the tips.</string>
    <string name="hand_lesson_4_description">Add small, short lines on the fingers and back of the hand to indicate where the knuckles and joints would be.</string>
    <string name="hand_lesson_5_description">Finally, erase your initial guidelines. Refine the lines, especially around the base of the thumb, to create a more natural and finished look.</string>
</resources>